<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</title>
    <link>/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 17:43:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keep Studying Never Stop</title>
      <link>/posts/keep-studyng-never-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 17:43:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/keep-studyng-never-stop/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-suggest-you-never-stop-studying&#34;&gt;Why I suggest you never stop studying!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of my career, searching for a profession, I was always very curious about computers, but with a limited income, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to study, buy computers, or have access to technology in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first job was painting bicycle handlebars, and I had no prospects. Later, I got a job managing the inventory of a candy store. With that, I made an agreement with my family that the little money I earned would go towards paying for college, and we all agreed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting college, a friend recommended me for an infrastructure job (internship), and without a second thought, &lt;strong&gt;I said YES YES YES, I WANT IT&lt;/strong&gt;! In the interview, &lt;strong&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t truthful, FEARING I MIGHT LOSE THE ONLY CHANCE&lt;/strong&gt;, and when they asked if I had ever swapped hard drives in servers, I said YES, OF COURSE!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, it was so simple, and I managed to do it without ever having done it before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in college, I simply fell in love with writing code. I always completed the projects and tasks, sometimes without sleeping, but I got them done, and with an indescribable joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I have become a software engineer, and I continue learning new technologies as if it were my first day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say, college helped my life in a way NOTHING else could have; it changed everything for the better! Sometimes I hear people say it’s not worth it, but I think the opposite—if you can or want to, do it without hesitation like I did in the past!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I’d like to say, despite fears in this new world of GenAI and the challenges that come with it, &lt;strong&gt;never, NEVER stop studying&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you need help, any mentoring, I can try to help you, just reach out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugs, and keep moving forward with your studies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
