<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Routine on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</title>
    <link>/tags/routine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Routine on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 16:59:52 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/routine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remember Life Is Not a 100 Meter Race</title>
      <link>/posts/remember-life-is-not-a-100-meter-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 16:59:52 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/remember-life-is-not-a-100-meter-race/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my life, I’ve often liked something and used it every day until I got sick of it.
But now, I’ve started therapy, and one of the first things I’ve learned is how to use a calendar to organize my routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By organizing my routine, I realized that I need to plan everything in advance—whether it’s for the week, month, or year.
For example, in my current routine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I exercise for one hour every weekday.
I study English two days a week, for one hour each day.
I spend 30 minutes every day reading books outside of my profession, among other activities.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part about organizing your week with clear goals is understanding that progress takes time.
I won’t learn English or Golang (a programming language) in a day or a week. However, by organizing my week, I can work toward these goals gradually and stay on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, I’ll show you how I organize my week. I hope it helps you organize yours too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/example-calendar.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I’ve structured my schedule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I exercise every day of the week.
I read every day.
I study a new technology every day.
I work regularly and ensure I spend quality time with my daughter and family.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I truly hope this helps you organize your week. It has been a great tool for managing anxiety and developing a long-term mindset. After all, life is not a 100-meter race!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you found this helpful and that it inspires you to organize your week too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
