<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</title>
    <link>/tags/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 17:36:05 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This Post Isn&#39;t About Technology</title>
      <link>/posts/this-post-isnt-about-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 17:36:05 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/this-post-isnt-about-technology/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-post-is-about-depth-of-knowledge&#34;&gt;This post is about depth of knowledge!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started my blog, I added Google Analytics—not to track performance,
but because I was curious about how people engage with my posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, as I’ve been writing for this blog, I’ve observed an interesting trend.
People seem to gravitate toward “ready-made recipes” or practical guides.
For instance, when I wrote posts about studying Golang or how Exercism helps me learn,
they attracted little attention. Similarly, posts about LeetCode, study techniques,
or my personal schedule and life routines didn’t generate much traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when I shared a step-by-step guide on using Swagger in a Golang API—essentially
a “recipe”—it became the most-viewed post in my blog’s history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/count_posts_view.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image above shows a visualization of my blog&amp;rsquo;s behavior over the past week. As we can see, the post about Swagger has received more than double the views of any other post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on this, if I could share one piece of advice, it would be this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treat your life as a long journey—a marathon, not a sprint. Organize your time,
study a little every day, and create a routine that helps you stay focused.
Aim for deep, meaningful learning, because acquiring deep knowledge is the best way to
secure a relatively stable future—free from fears and uncertainties, even about challenges like AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxsoares.github.io/posts/remember-life-is-not-a-100-meter-race/&#34;&gt;In the post&lt;/a&gt; where I compare life to a
marathon rather than a 100-meter sprint, I share how my routine works in the hope of helping and
motivating you to organize your life and focus on the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post isn’t meant as criticism—think of it as friendly advice!
As the poet says, “If advice were truly valuable, it would be sold, not given away.”
Yet, here I am, offering it freely in an effort to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed this post and that it inspires or helps you in some way!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
