<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</title>
    <link>/categories/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 18:50:05 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Can AI Change the Way We Work</title>
      <link>/posts/how-can-ai-change-the-way-we-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 18:50:05 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-can-ai-change-the-way-we-work/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first answer is, I DON’T KNOW! Bye-bye! (Just kidding! Keep reading, please! It was only a joke!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I saw the new Canvas feature from OpenAI, and I’m feeling two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m very excited about the evolution of AI and the new possibilities it can bring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m also a bit scared by the rapid advancement of AI and the potential changes it could bring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the first point. I use AI daily to help me write code at work. But of course, I don’t just copy and paste the AI-generated code into my editor (I use Zed). Instead, I use AI to resolve my doubts and assist me when I need to write in programming languages I’m less experienced with. This is amazing—it’s like having a knowledgeable assistant right by my side!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, for the second point. I have a daughter, and I’m worried about the future that AI might create for her. What will my profession look like in the medium and long term? Will I still have a job?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only certainty I have is that no profession will be the same after the use of AI. Whether it will improve, worsen, or cease to exist, we do not know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these concerns, I believe the key is to keep learning and staying up to date with the latest technologies. We need to be prepared for the new challenges that lie ahead. AI is a tool that can help us create and complete tasks with greater speed and quality, but it’s up to us to continue improving our skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as I said in another article, don&amp;rsquo;t stop studying, stay focused and studying!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what do you think? How do you feel about AI and the new possibilities it brings?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Studying Never Stop</title>
      <link>/posts/keep-studyng-never-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 17:43:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/keep-studyng-never-stop/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-suggest-you-never-stop-studying&#34;&gt;Why I suggest you never stop studying!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of my career, searching for a profession, I was always very curious about computers, but with a limited income, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to study, buy computers, or have access to technology in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first job was painting bicycle handlebars, and I had no prospects. Later, I got a job managing the inventory of a candy store. With that, I made an agreement with my family that the little money I earned would go towards paying for college, and we all agreed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting college, a friend recommended me for an infrastructure job (internship), and without a second thought, &lt;strong&gt;I said YES YES YES, I WANT IT&lt;/strong&gt;! In the interview, &lt;strong&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t truthful, FEARING I MIGHT LOSE THE ONLY CHANCE&lt;/strong&gt;, and when they asked if I had ever swapped hard drives in servers, I said YES, OF COURSE!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, it was so simple, and I managed to do it without ever having done it before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in college, I simply fell in love with writing code. I always completed the projects and tasks, sometimes without sleeping, but I got them done, and with an indescribable joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I have become a software engineer, and I continue learning new technologies as if it were my first day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say, college helped my life in a way NOTHING else could have; it changed everything for the better! Sometimes I hear people say it’s not worth it, but I think the opposite—if you can or want to, do it without hesitation like I did in the past!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I’d like to say, despite fears in this new world of GenAI and the challenges that come with it, &lt;strong&gt;never, NEVER stop studying&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you need help, any mentoring, I can try to help you, just reach out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugs, and keep moving forward with your studies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senior Software Engineer</title>
      <link>/posts/senior-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:37:38 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/senior-software-engineer/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;senior-software-engineers-impacting-business-growth-and-inspiring-teams&#34;&gt;Senior Software Engineers: Impacting Business Growth and Inspiring Teams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started as a Software Engineer, I skipped the internal steps because my initial experience in tech was with infrastructure, not programming. I transitioned into software engineering four years later, and when I finally worked as a Software Engineer, I was very fortunate. My coworkers were exceptional professionals who supported me at the beginning of my journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Senior Software Engineer now, I strive every day to be like those mentors and positively impact the people I work with. Knowing the business you work in better than anyone else enables you to help those around you and be an outstanding professional wherever you go.
A phrase that I always remember to impact the people around me is, always be the senior you wish you had met when you were a junior. This phrase has helped me to be a better professional and to help others in their journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This text is to invite you to be the senior you wish you had met when you were a junior. Be the professional who helps others and makes a difference in the lives of those around you.
And a few years later, if you follow this tip every day, you will see incredible people, being excellent professionals because in the past, they were lucky enough to meet you, who impacted them positively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be the best version of yourself every day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
