<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on I&#39;m Jane Doe</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on I&#39;m Jane Doe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:37:38 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Senior Software Engineer</title>
      <link>/posts/senior-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:37:38 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/senior-software-engineer/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;senior-software-engineers-impacting-business-growth-and-inspiring-teams&#34;&gt;Senior Software Engineers: Impacting Business Growth and Inspiring Teams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started as a Software Engineer, I skipped the internal steps because my initial experience in tech was with infrastructure, not programming. I transitioned into software engineering four years later, and when I finally worked as a Software Engineer, I was very fortunate. My coworkers were exceptional professionals who supported me at the beginning of my journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Senior Software Engineer now, I strive every day to be like those mentors and positively impact the people I work with. Knowing the business you work in better than anyone else enables you to help those around you and be an outstanding professional wherever you go.
A phrase that I always remember to impact the people around me is, always be the senior you wish you had met when you were a junior. This phrase has helped me to be a better professional and to help others in their journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Clojure Project</title>
      <link>/posts/first-clojure-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 18:04:37 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first-clojure-project/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;creating-our-first-clojure-project&#34;&gt;Creating Our First Clojure Project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s continue with our tutorial. Today, I will explain how we can create a Clojure project. I decided to split this article into two parts: we will explain how to create a regular project and a web project, where we will create an API for some service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start by creating a regular project. It won&amp;rsquo;t be an API, a library, or anything like that. I just want to demonstrate how to create a project, explain its structure, and everything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>