<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal-Growth on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</title>
    <link>/tags/personal-growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal-Growth on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 16:40:03 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/personal-growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Going Against the Flow of the World</title>
      <link>/posts/going_against_the_flow_of_the_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 16:40:03 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/going_against_the_flow_of_the_world/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my country, this week marks the start of &amp;ldquo;Black Week,&amp;rdquo; although the correct term is &amp;ldquo;Black Friday,&amp;rdquo;
traditionally a single day of discounts in stores. As you know,
I’m a software engineer, and this week I’ve noticed many courses on sale,
offering a variety of options for learning new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this time, I’ve been reflecting on these courses and the increasingly fast-paced world
we live in—a world where everyone feels the need to learn quickly and where courses
often promise accelerated learning. I’ve decided that, as a human being, I shouldn’t follow this path of speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, anyone who has gained deep knowledge in a subject has done so through
years of study and consistent practice. I believe this should remain the standard today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this post isn’t about avoiding buying courses or learning materials altogether.
Instead, it’s about embracing the process of learning gradually, a little every day, and resisting
the pressure to conform to the fast-paced trends of the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I’d like to share my decision this Black Friday week:
I’ve decided not to buy any courses or materials that promise faster, easier,
or miraculous results. Instead, I’ll continue reading my books, sticking to the routine
I shared &lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxsoares.github.io/posts/remember-life-is-not-a-100-meter-race/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and focusing on learning slowly and deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you make the most of this week of discounts where you live and take the opportunity to plan ahead,
focusing on a path that considers the medium and long term and that this post inspires you to reflect on
your learning process and the path you’re taking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugs! 🤗&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
