<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</title>
    <link>/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on I&#39;m Gilmar Soares</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:54:50 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Year, Same Consistency</title>
      <link>/posts/new_year_same_consistency/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:54:50 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new_year_same_consistency/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone, welcome to the new year! Let&amp;rsquo;s make this a year of consistency and growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is January 6, 2026. I’ve been reading about creating to-do lists for yearly goals, and it has made me think about how vital it is to stay consistent in our actions. While I often read about the importance of setting &amp;ldquo;New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions,&amp;rdquo; I rarely see anyone talk about creating a to-do list for your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe that New Year’s Eve alone can change someone, or that you can achieve something just because you start with a burst of willpower. Instead, I believe that if you have a desire—for example, learning a new language—you should create a plan, strive for weekly consistency, and refuse to give up until you reach that goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this year, I hope you believe in yourself more than in a number changing on the calendar. I hope you challenge yourself, make a plan, and actually follow it. I also hope you respect your limits without putting too much pressure on yourself; simply follow the plan and learn to enjoy the journey, not just the result. I guarantee that this mindset will change your life more than the passing years ever could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use your schedule to organize your plan and try to respect the time blocks you’ve chosen, whether it’s 30 minutes or an hour. The most important thing is to be consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is often much harder to stick to a long-term plan than it is to do a lot at the beginning and quit a week later. But the truth is, if you can stay consistent over time, you will see incredible changes. And of course, the real secret is this: if you love the process, nothing and no one can stop you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2026 and for the rest of your life, I wish you consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugs!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remember Life Is Not a 100 Meter Race</title>
      <link>/posts/remember-life-is-not-a-100-meter-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 16:59:52 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/remember-life-is-not-a-100-meter-race/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my life, I’ve often liked something and used it every day until I got sick of it.
But now, I’ve started therapy, and one of the first things I’ve learned is how to use a calendar to organize my routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By organizing my routine, I realized that I need to plan everything in advance—whether it’s for the week, month, or year.
For example, in my current routine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I exercise for one hour every weekday.
I study English two days a week, for one hour each day.
I spend 30 minutes every day reading books outside of my profession, among other activities.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part about organizing your week with clear goals is understanding that progress takes time.
I won’t learn English or Golang (a programming language) in a day or a week. However, by organizing my week, I can work toward these goals gradually and stay on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, I’ll show you how I organize my week. I hope it helps you organize yours too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/example-calendar.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I’ve structured my schedule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I exercise every day of the week.
I read every day.
I study a new technology every day.
I work regularly and ensure I spend quality time with my daughter and family.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I truly hope this helps you organize your week. It has been a great tool for managing anxiety and developing a long-term mindset. After all, life is not a 100-meter race!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you found this helpful and that it inspires you to organize your week too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
